本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigamiorg)制作仅供交流学习禁止用于任何商业用途
日听：小伍King翻译：森罗小江校对：Syura时间轴：海底压制：Coolkid
アウト
It went out of bounds!
So lucky!
Karasuno                    Aoba Jousai
青城から第１セト獲た
We won the first set against Seijou!
We took the first set!
１セト先取
All right!
Take the second set too!
２セト目ものてけ
Sorry.
サセン
That idiot!
こいつ明らかに金田一のボルだたのに
Not only was that obviously Kindaichi's ball,
but then he steals it only to hit it out of bounds?!
ぶんどた挙げ句アウトかよ
On top of that, they were at set point!
しかも今のセトポイントだたんだぞ
How can I even start to explain?!
一体どからつ込めばい
What you did was dangerous!
危ねぇだろうが
Iwaizumi!
岩泉
そうそうそれそれまずそれね
Yeah, that's it! That needs to be said first!
Oh, I'm perfectly fine...
俺は大丈夫なんで
I was stressed because I had to stand on the sidelines for so long.
試合出してもらえないからストレス溜まてたんで
それて理由になてないから
That's not a valid reason!
What's with that guy?
なんだあいつ
Why would Seijou swap in a guy like that?
あんな奴投入して青城どうした
Aoba Jousai                    Karasuno
Oh, it's that guy from earlier.
さきの奴いる
He must be starting this set.
今度はスタティングからか
Since he's replacing Kunimi,
he might be pretty quick on his feet.
国見の代わりてことはけこう頭のきれる奴なのかも
Be careful.
気をつけろ
You're more or less free to play how you want,
but if you get in our way, you'll be back on the bench.
お前は基本好きにやてていいけど
足引張るなら引込めるからな
無駄に危ないプレだけはすんじゃねぇぞ
Just don't do anything dangerous like before.
Right.
Why did you only reply to Iwa?!
なんで岩ちゃんにだけ返事すんだよ
He challenged Iwaizumi every chance he got and lost every single time,
あいつ岩泉さんに色々と勝負ふかけて
ことごとく負けてから岩泉さんにだけは従うのな
so Iwaizumi is the only person he obeys.
Arm Wresting Contest
Not so fast!
What are we, a wolf pack?
甘ぇ
狼社会的な
Well, the one who'll be putting him to use is Oikawa.
まぁ実際に使うのは及川さんなんだけどな
That's true.
ですね
Let's ride this momentum and settle the score!
このままの勢いで一気に決める
We're gonna win the second set too!
２セト目も獲るぞ
Yeah!
Episode Twenty-one:
The Destroyer
You can do this, Asahi!
旭さん一発ナイサ
Let it go!
アウト
Damn it! Sorry!
くそすまん
So close! You'll get the next one!
惜しい次次
Shake it off!
ドンマイです
Your face is scary!
顔怖ぇ
なんだと
What'd you say?!
Give us a good one, Oikawa!
Aoba Jousai                    Karasuno
及川ナイサ
アウトアウト
It's going out!
ごめん
Sorry!
ドンマイ次一本
It's fine! We'll get the next one!
I wonder what's wrong with Oikawa.
及川くんどうしたんだろ
He messed up another serve.
またサブミス
He hits the ball so hard, though.
でもすごいスピド触たら腕もげちゃうね
Touching it would tear off your arms.
I think his aim is slowly getting better.
段々照準合わせてきてる気がする
Give us a good serve, Tsukishima!
月島ナイサ
Bastard!
ヤロウ
Nice save, Iwa!
サイスカバ岩ちゃん
前衛は攻撃３枚誰来る
There are three attackers in the front row.
Who's it gonna be?
狂犬ちゃん
Mad Dog!
ライトからのオプン
An open set to the right?!
What the heck is "Mad Dog"?!
狂犬てなんだ
Is that his nickname?
もしや異名かけぇ
That's so awesome!
Block it!
ブロク一本
What?
なんだ
He's sprinting basically parallel to the net?!
ネトのほぼ真横からの助走
ブロク３枚
Three blockers!
超インナスパイク
That cut shot was insane!
So that's why he made that approach.
だからあの助走か
Huh?
ブロクと向かい合う形になると
When you face the blockers head-on,
you have some options for where to hit it,
コスの選択肢はあるけど
but chances are you'll get blocked.
当然ブロクにぶち当たりやすくなるじゃん
Instead, he hit it to cut across the blockers.
でも今ブロクの横から切り込むみたいに打たわけよ
He comes in from the right and hits with his right hand,
pulling off that incredible cut shot.
ライト側から右手で打つからこその極端なインナスパイクだな
Wow!
Mad Dog is amazing!
狂犬すげぇ
Aoba Jousai                    Karasuno
岩泉ナイサ
Give us a good one, Iwaizumi!
It's coming back over! We can score here!
返てくるチャンスボル
くそすまん
Damn it! Sorry!
Oikawa and Iwaizumi serving back-to-back is putting a lot of pressure on them.
及川と岩泉のサブが続くのはけこうなプレシャだな
オライ
Got it!
And on top of that, there's also Mad Dog.
それに加えて狂犬か
A double quick attack?!
ダブルクイク
All right!
よしゃあ
いぞいぞ賢太郎押せ押せ賢太郎もう一本
いくら「狂犬」でもそう何回も噛みついてこないから
I know he's a mad dog, but he's not going to keep biting forever, so you can come inside.
躊躇わず入てきなて
Shorty caught on that you weren't going to hit it, Kindaichi.
打つのが金田一じゃないてチビちゃんにバレてたぞ
Sorry! I chickened out a bit there!
すんませんちょとビビりました
Give us another good serve, Iwa!
岩ちゃんもう一本ナイサ
Yeah!
しゃあ
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
C Quick!
Ｃクイク
だ大丈夫か
Y-You okay?!
Y-Yeah, I'm fine. Totally fine.
大丈夫大丈夫
It's number sixteen again!
またあの１６番
３連続得点
That's three points in a row!
決まてはいても乱暴にも見える連携攻撃
Even though his spikes are landing, they seem pretty violent.
Ever since number sixteen subbed in,
the rhythm of their attacks has changed.
１６番が入てから攻撃のリズムが変わた
Nice spike, Kyoutani!
京谷ナイスキな
Give us another good serve, Iwaizumi!
Aoba Jousai                  Karasuno
岩泉もう一本ナイサ
すまん
Sorry!
しゃあ
All right!
We finally got a point back.
やと一点返した
Nice, Makki!
マキナイス
Here he comes!
来た
勝負だ狂犬
You're on, Mad Dog!
１６番に派手に攻撃させてからの
After number sixteen makes a few flashy attacks,
it's a broad jump from Kindaichi!
金田一のブロド
All right!
いぞいぞ勇太郎押せ押せ勇太郎もう一本
He's angry that he was used as a decoy.
自分が囮にされることに腹を立てている
That anger just makes him a better decoy, though.
その攻撃への執着心が囮の効力を上げているんだけどね
I'll make those fangs of yours even sharper.
その牙俺がもと鋭くしてやる
シメて行こう
Let's play carefully.
That team isn't the Seijou we're familiar with.
あれは俺達の知らない青城だ
Aoba Jousai                             Karasuno
Give us a good serve, Kindaichi!
金田一ナイサ
オライ
Got it!
Left!
Center!
レフト
センタ
So their strategy is to always have a middle blocker on Hinata?
日向には必ずミドルブロカ一人が張り付くスタイルか
上がたカバ
It's up! Get it!
Got it! Finish it off, Kyoutani!
オライ
京谷ラスト
Sorry! It's close to the net!
ワリネト近ぇ
Three blockers!
ブロク３枚
If he spikes, they'll block it.
打てば捕まる
Hit it back to us!
一回返して
Nice block!
All right!
ナイスブロク
That was an amazingly brave spike.
潔いほどのフルスイングすね
That idiot...
あいつ
バカお前もうちょい軟打とかフェイントとかあるだろう
Dumbass! You could've done a soft hit or tipped it over!
An attack doesn't feel right if I don't hit it as hard as I can!
攻撃は強打が決まんなきゃ気持ちよくねぇす
You little...
Now, now, Mizoguchi.
まあまあ溝口くん
What needs to be corrected will be corrected in due time.
正すところはいずれ正すよ
Right.
頭がきれる奴とは
What were you saying about him being smart?
I just thought that he might be!
かもつただけすよ
フェイントの快感を知らないとはもたいない奴め
He doesn't know how good it feels to get a nice tip off!
What a shame.
Aoba Jousai                 Karasuno
Makki!
Nice one, Nishinoya!
ナイス西谷
Nice, Makki!
ナイスマキ
Mad Dog!
狂犬ちゃん
He's coming in from the side again!
また横から打ち込んでくるやつ
I'm going to stop him this time!
今度こそ止める
All right!
よしゃ
What a relief.
助かた
I guess trying to bust through three blockers via a narrow gap with a powerful spike has its risks.
３枚ブロクに付かれて狭いコスを強打で抜くには
それなりにリスクがあるてことだな
あのアクの強そうな感じと不安定さ
That attack is powerful but unreliable.
Since he didn't start in any matches so far,
ここまで試合に出ていなかたところから見ても
he might be something of a double-edged sword.
あの１６番は諸刃の剣なのかもな
Number sixteen's spike...
あの１６番のスパイク
Hm?
グインギュンて感じでかこいいです
It was all "whoosh" and "boom"!
It's so cool!
Isn't it?
そうだろうそうだろう
Of course, Mad Dog can jump high, as well as
having unbelievable dorsal and abdominal muscles.
狂犬ちゃんにあるのはジャンプ力は当然
並外れた背筋腹筋
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
He arches back to build up power, and then he lets it all loose!
ぐと反て溜めを作りそこから弾き出す
He really packs a punch.
強烈だろ
If he gets through a block, the ball won't be easy to dig out.
ブロク抜けたらそうそう拾えないよ
All right!
He finally got one in.
しゃあ
やと決また
Oikawa used him well.
及川よく使いましたね
If it were me, I would've given the ball to someone else.
俺だたら一回他に回しちまう
Tenacity and boldness.
粘り強くかつ大胆に
You can't utilize Mad Dog if you're timid.
おかなびくりしていては京谷は使えないからな
Give us a good one, Kyoutani!
京谷ナイサ
Let it go!
アウト
All right!
しゃあ
サブもまたダイナミクで
His serve is quite dynamic too.
Nice call!
ナイスジャジ
Aoba Jousai                 Karasuno
Such a back-and-forth match.
一進一退
It's basically a stalemate.
膠着状態だな
Yeah.
なああの１６番決める割にミスも多いからな
Number sixteen's spikes are impressive, but he messes them up often.
しゃあ
All right!
岩泉さんナイサ
Give us a good one, Iwaizumi!
Someone get it!
マキラスト
Finish it, Makki!
Got it!
オライ
もかいもかい
Let's go again!
He messed up the receive!
レシブ乱れた
Watch the left side!
レフト来るぞ
わざとだよ
That was on purpose.
Mad Dog!
狂犬今までよりタイミング早い
His timing's faster than before!
セカンドテンポ
It's second tempo!
I'm well aware that he's a double-edged sword!
諸刃の剣は百も承知
All the more reason to make the best use his strengths!
だからこそ生かしてみせる
All right!
よぉし
What a crazy angle.
えげつない角度だ
自分の手でブロクひぺがすのはセタならではの快感だよな
Only a setter can know how good it feels to peel away the blockers using your own skill.
Get on it!
喰らいついてけ
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
Center!
センタ
Aoba Jousai               Karasuno
翔陽ナイサ
Give us a good serve, Shouyou!
Hinata, give it all you've got!
日向思いきり行けよ
またスパイク打てないまま後衛か
I rotated to the back row without spiking again.
Got it!
オライ
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
よし行くぜ
All right! Let's do this!
日向のバクアタク
Hinata's doing a back row attack!
My first back row attack!
初バクアタク
Yeah!
よしゃあ
今が使い時だて思た
Did you think now was your opportunity to use that?
So did I.
俺も思た
平常心平常心平常心
Keep calm, keep calm, keep calm...
That was my back row attack's debut...
俺のバクアタクデビュ
ブレイクできるかと思たのに
I thought they could score two in a row.
If they don't start catching up soon, they'll be in trouble.
この点差つめないとまずいな
Oh!
Huh?
Sugawara got called over to the bench?
菅原がベンチ呼ばれた
Are they changing setters again?
またセタ代えんのかな影山は調子悪くなさそうだけど
Kageyama seems to be doing fine.
What happened now wasn't his fault.
Oikawa is just really good.
今のは及川すげぇてだけで
Actually, I don't think they're switching out Kageyama.
いや交替する番号たぶん影山じゃない
このまま持てかせねぇぞ
I won't let them run away with this.
やれることは全部やる
We're going to do everything we can first.
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
H
a
S
e
i
c
k
y
o
n
u
d
S
e
!
a
s
o
n
菅原さんが誰かと交替てことですか
Is Sugawara switching with someone?
戦術的選手交替だな
It's a tactical player substitution.
Please don't use such big words.
漢字いぱい使わないで
おい大学生
Aren't you in college?
You know how substitutions can happen
when someone's not doing well or gets hurt,
交替て不調とか怪我でする場合と
or how there are times where a pinch server or single-point blocker goes in, right?
ピンチサバとかワンポイントブロカを入れる場合があるだろ
後者が戦術的選手交替
The latter two are tactical player substitutions.
All right!
Aoba Jousai                    Karasuno
よしゃあ
Nice spike, Iwaizumi!
岩泉ナイスキ
前回の青城戦は
In their previous match against Seijou, they were cornered and ended up being forced to switch him in.
追い詰められて苦肉の策的な交替の使い方だたけど
But this time, they're most likely doing it offensively.
今回はたぶん勝ちを取りに行くための交替だ
Number sixteen is a bit of an unknown,
so dealing with Seijou has gotten even harder.
１６番という異物が入て対応が更に難しくなてる
だがこのまま持てかせやしねぇぞ
But we're not going to just let them have it.
Yes, but before that...
でもその前に
Give us a good serve, Oikawa!
及川ナイサ
Oh, here it comes.
あ来た
That's a nice serve toss.
サブトスいい感じ
All right!
よしゃあ
It's like getting slapped in the face really hard
顔思いきり引叩かれて
現実に引き戻されるような感覚
and snapping back to reality.
勝ちを譲れないのはお互い様で
Neither of us can let the other win,
and we've both trained for that purpose.
そのための鍛錬をしてきたのもお互い様
It all makes sense.
至極当然のこと
当然のことでこんなにも恐ろしい事実
It's an obvious fact, yet the reality is so terrifying.
Aoba Jousai                    Karasuno
もう一本ナイサ
Give us another good serve!
Up front!
前
Damn it! I held back too much!
クソ身構えすぎた
ナイスレシブ西谷
Nice receive, Nishinoya!
レフト
Left!
Tanaka!
田中さん
ブロク３枚
Three blockers!
All right!
しゃあ
龍よくやた
Good one, Ryuu!
あ来た交替だ
Oh, here it is.
The substitution.
All right! We're gonna catch up now!
よしゃ追いつくぞ
Yeah!
ウェイ
Suga, we need a good serve here!
スガナイサ頼むぞ
Yep.
Bring it!
さあ来い
Give us a good serve, Suga!
スガさんナイサ
Serving right after you get subbed in sure is nerve-racking.
入ていきなしサブはやぱ緊張すんな
But there's only one place to aim for.
でも狙うところは一つ
京谷
Kyoutani!
That was good!
うまい
Now number sixteen can't make it in time for a spike!
これで１６番が攻撃に出遅れた
All right!
They scored!
Aoba Jousai                    Karasuno
ブレイク
スガさんもう一本ナイサ
Give us another good serve, Suga!
Again?!
京谷はウィングスパイカだが
Kyoutani is a wing spiker, but he's the type who goes for one fast attack after another.
ガンガン速攻に入てくるタイプ
サブで京谷を動かしスパイクの助走を牽制
They're getting him to move to receive serves so that he's out of position for spikes.
What an annoying tactic from Karasuno's number two!
烏野の２番嫌なところに打てきやがる
Nice receive, Daichi!
大地さんナイスレシブ
All right!
よしゃあ
Yes!
影山が攻撃に下がた
Kageyama pulled back from an attack?
Five Karasuno spikers?!
烏野のスパイカ
五枚
Yeah!
しゃあ
N-Nice spike...
ナイナイス
チクショウ影山ストレトうめぇ
Damn it. Kageyama's straight spike is awesome!
今のはツセタてやつでしょうか
Was that just now what you call a two-setter formation?
Ugh, even more jargon...
また新しい単語
Then...
戦術的ワンポイントツセタだな
It's a tactical single point by two setters!
Right?
長いわ
That's too long.
All right!
よし後１点
Aoba Jousai                  Karasuno
Just one more point!
よしゃあ
All right!
行け行け行け行け行け青城
They're really in the groove after that well-timed player substitution.
このタイミングの選手交替うまいことはまたな
All of the third-years are good at receiving.
押せ押せ押せ押せ押せ青城
やぱ３年ともなるとレシブうまいな
I see!
なるほど
Net
Server
バレはロテションシステムで常にプレヤの位置が回る
Volleyball works on a rotational system where each player's position on the court constantly changes.
前衛と後衛では役割も変わるから
The front row and back row have different jobs, so each rotation has certain strengths.
ロテによて特徴があんのね
And apparently,
そして恐らく
Server
Net
月島サブの時のロテが守備でも攻撃でも谷間と言える
the rotation where Tsukishima is serving is weak for both offense and defense.
前衛にはスパイカが２枚しかいないし
There are only two spikers in front,
Server
and Tsukishima can't block from the back.
月島は後衛でブロク不可
Server
行け行け行け行け行け青城
今まで凌ぐだけだたロテで
So considering their rotation,
it's quite a feat that they were able to keep scoring.
積極的に点が取れるてことには大きな意味があるよ
押せ押せ押せ押せ押せ青城
Well, what's it going to be?
さてどうしよか
How about we pull him back?
じゃ外せば
Yeah.
Give us another good serve, Suga!
スガさんもう一本ナイサ
They're going after Kyoutani again!
やはり京谷狙い
Got it!
オライ
Nice, Makki!
マキナイス
They always figure out a solution so quickly!
相変わらず対応早ぇな
All right!
よしゃあ
Nice work, Suga!
スガさんナイスす
Thanks.
Damn it.
クソ同点までは持ていきたかた
I wanted to tie the match up.
Aoba Jousai                    Karasuno
Tanaka!
田中さん
しゃあ
Yeah!
影山ナイサ
Give us a good one, Kageyama!
岩ちゃん
Iwa!
He got it!
拾いやがた
Watacchi!
渡ち
Right!
All right!
よしゃあ
How do I put this?
なんつか
少し不自然なくらい攻撃を１６番に集めてる感じしねぇ
Doesn't it feel like they're concentrating an unnatural amount of their offense on number sixteen?
Yeah, it does.
ああだよな
１６番に注目させといてからまた他にふるて感じかもな
Maybe they're trying to get all the attention on number sixteen so they can hand it off to someone else later.
No matter how many times Mad Dog spikes, I'm not gonna get tricked anymore!
どんなに狂犬にボルが集まても今度は騙されないからな
田中さん
Tanaka!
Got it!
オライ
Nice, Makki!
ナイスマキ
I know why we subbed Kyoutani in.
京谷を入れる理由は分かている
俺たち後一歩欲しいパンチ力
It's for the little extra punch we needed to improve our offense.
攻撃のために入たんだ
狂犬ちゃん
Mad Dog!
存分に発揮してもらわないと困る
If we don't use him to his fullest, we're in trouble!
All right!
よしゃあ
Damn it...
Here come the points!
かかてきたかかてきた
いいとこなのに
Hey, it was just getting good!
行け行け行け行け行け青城
They reached twenty points first.
先に２０点台に乗られちまたか
Even if they lose this set,
Karasuno already won the first one.
もしこのセト落としても
烏野は先に１セト取てるし
押せ押せ押せ押せ押せ青城
次取れば大丈夫大丈夫
As long as they take the next set, they'll be fine.
No.
It's better to take this set by any means necessary.
このセトは意地でも取たほうがいい
このまま一気に行くよ
We're gonna finish this!
Yeah!
I have a bad feeling about the outcome if they don't.
取らないとまずい気がする
Give us another good serve, Kindaichi!
金田一もう一本ナイサ
前
Up front!
すすんません
S-Sorry!
Don't overthink it.
狙いすぎたな
Here we go!
行くぞ
田中ナイサ
Give us a good one, Tanaka!
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
All right!
よしゃあ
Trying not to think about something is no different than actually thinking about it.
意識しないよう努めるのも意識するのと一緒だよ
Aoba Jousai                             Karasuno
京谷ナイサ
Give us a good serve, Kyoutani!
Bring it!
さあ来い
All right!
よしゃあ
諸刃の剣
The double-edged sword...
１６番を入れること自体が青城にとて一か八かの賭けで
Subbing in number sixteen was the sink-or-swim moment for Seijou,
but I thought he had a proven track record.
でもそれは既に成功しているのだと思ていた
Sir!
先生
Yes!
よしゃあ
All right!
また早
Again? That was fast!
烏野タイムアウト使い切たな
Now Karasuno's used up all of their timeouts.
１６番という新しい武器で撹乱
With number sixteen as their new weapon,
they racked up points in a disturbingly certain manner.
確実に得点を重ねながら
Yet it turns out they were using most of this set to bring him up to speed?
このセトの大半をかけて１６番の調子を上げてきたのか
京谷は手のかかるスロスタタだが
Kyoutani is slow to get going and needs lots of support.
かかれば強い
But once he does, he's quite impressive.
This isn't good.
まずいぞ
The mood of a match can have a huge impact on the next set.
試合の特にセト終盤の雰囲気ていうのは
次のセトにも影響していくことがある
How the previous set ended is especially vital.
今のままじゃ確実に青城有利
Let's bring it in!
Seijou definitely has the upper hand right now.
しめてくぞ烏野ファイ
Karasuno, fight!
なんとかこのセト獲て収めてくれ
Karasuno needs to do whatever it takes to win this set and end it!
Yeah!
Give us another good one, Kyoutani!
京谷もう一本ナイサ
Let's get this one!
一本取るぞ
Yeah!
うせぇな分かてるよ
Stop bugging me.
I already know.
俺に行かせてください
Please put me in there!
Looks like your engine's warming up, Mad Dog.
エンジンかかてきたね狂犬ちゃん
Let's finish this!
このまま一気に行くよ
京谷このセト一気に取るぞ
Kyoutani, we're gonna take this set.
Right.
Why do you only answer Iwa?!
なんで岩ちゃんにだけ返事すんのさ
I'm not gonna set for you anymore!
もうトスあげてやんない
次回ハイキュ元根性無しの戦い
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
Episode Twenty-two:
The Fight of the Previously Spineless
"The Fight of the Previously Spineless."